### 432 My Street, Augusta, ME 21098 s.milne@myemail.com (321) 098-7654

# Scott Milne

#### **PROFILE**

Seasoned school librarian with 10+ years' experience selecting and managing varied collections, including digital resource databases. Strong teaching ability and dedication to promoting a culture of reading and literature appreciation among students. Extensive knowledge of disability adaptations with a proven track record for ensuring equal access for students with barriers to learning.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **School Librarian**

Augusta School Department, Augusta, ME | September 2014 - Present

- Select, purchase, and catalog diverse materials, including literature, reference books, publications, and digital resources
- provide student orientation services and offer guidance on using databases to locate resources
- Plan and run events and activities that foster a love of books and reading skills, including author talks, reading circles, and remedial comprehension classes
- Handle the departmental budget and oversee staff training and performance management

#### **School Librarian**

Portland Public Schools, Portland ME | September 2010-August 2014

- Selected stock to reflect the cultures, educational needs, and ages of students in collaboration with librarians from other schools
- Ensured appealing and orderly organization of materials and created rotating displays to reflect the educational role of the library and mark significant events
- Managed the schools ICT suite and provided student training to allow them to access the library's digital resource archives
- Adapted the library environment and resources to make them accessible to students with special educational needs

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Bachelor of Arts in English**

University Of Southern Maine, Portland, Me September 2004 - June 2008

## Master of Science in Library and Information Science

The Catholic University Of America, Washington, De September 2008 - June 2010

#### **KEY SKILLS**

- Content selection and cataloging
- Budget management
- Staff training and deployment
- · Teaching literacy skills